# Ayodele Ajayi

Camden, England, United Kingdom



ayoinc@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/ayoinc

#### Summary

A bright, talented and ambitious SRE/DevOps/SysOps / Security / Application specialist with a strong technical background who possesses self-discipline and the ability to work with the minimum of supervision. Having exposure to a wide range of technologies & able to play a key role in diagnosing hardware, software problems, analyse network logs for security and to ensure that quality solutions meet business objectives. Possessing a good team spirit, deadline orientated and having the ability to organize and present complex solutions clearly and accurately.

#### **Experience**



#### Site Reliability Engineer

The Rank Group plc

Mar 2020 - Present (9 months +)

Implementing globally used processes and procedures, monitoring solutions, and building a Site Reliability. Increasing operational up-time of websites and technical services.

# DevOps Engineer

Adjoint Inc.

Aug 2019 - Mar 2020 (8 months)

Ops for FinTech / Smart Ledger Solution

# 🦰 IT Engineer

**OpenAsset** 

Jan 2018 - Aug 2019 (1 year 8 months)

Supporting OpenAsset Digital Asset Management Software in Cloud and OnPremise Clients

# System Analyst (IT Contractor)

Indivior

Mar 2016 - Jan 2018 (1 year 11 months)

# Senior IT Analyst

SC Johnson

Aug 2015 - Mar 2016 (8 months)

#### IT Support Technician / Multimedia

New Testament Church of God Clare Valley

Dec 2012 - Jun 2015 (2 years 7 months)

#### IT and System Support Technician

Guardian Newspaper Nigeria
Mar 2011 - Apr 2012 (1 year 2 months)

Contract / Temporary Position

#### **Education**



#### Harvard University

Certificate, Cybersecurity: Managing Risk in the Information Age

2017 - 2018

Centered on:

- \* Using Cyber risk management to mitigate Cyberattacks
- \* Identifying cyber threats to crucial business systems and data
- \* Vulnerability assessment on business systems, networks, and data
- \* Building a cybersecurity leadership plan
- \* Generating questions to determine money invested in a business cybersecurity
- \* Distinguish the legal and compliance risk for an organization
- \* Propose an incident response plan to prepare an organization in the event of an attack.
- \* Designing and implementing a risk mitigation strategy.

#### The Open University

Professional Development, Cyber Security for Small and Medium Businesses 2016 - 2016

Designed for System Analysts and Network Engineers

# Readynez

Professional Development, Project Management

2016 - 2016

PRINCE2

# Capital College UK

Diploma, Business, Management, Marketing, and Related Support Services 2012 - 2013

Association of Business Executives

# New Horizons Computer Learning Centre

Dip. Multimedia Technology, Multimedia Technology

2012 - 2012

Adobe Photoshop, Flash CS6, Indesign, Dreamweaver & Adobe Flash

# Dalewares Institute of Technology

National Innovative Diploma, Multimedia Technology

2009 - 2012 Multimedia Technology

# HP Online Learning Center

High School, Wireless Networking 2007 - 2008 Hewlett Packard Online Distance Learning Center

# Tomoriware Computer Institute

Diploma, Computer Installation and Repair Technology/Technician 2006 - 2007 Computer Repairs and Maintenance

### Oshodi Comprehensive High School

High School, Senior Secondary School Certificate 1996 - 2002 Mathematics, English Language, Physics, Chemistry, Geography, Yoruba Language

#### **Licenses & Certifications**

- National Ordinary Diploma National Board For Technical Education
- **PRINCE2 Foundation** APMG International PRINCE209092016
- National Innovative Diploma National Board for Technical Education NID001012009
- Windows Server 2012 Administration Udemy
- Active Directory & Group Policy 2012 Lab Udemy
- Securing Windows 10 LinkedIn
- Kali Linux for Penetration Testing LinkedIn
- in Introduction to Ethical Hacking LinkedIn
- Cyber Security Fundamentals The Open University FutureLearn
- ★ Fundamentals of Network Security Alison Free Online Learning

- Cyber Security for Small and Medium Enterprises: Identifying Threats and Preventing Attacks Deakin University FutureLearn
- Cyber Security Economics Technische Universiteit Delft 459b5b32b36044f496007512fac769fd
- Windows Server Administration Certified 2017 Microsoft
- Networking Fundamentals Certified 2017 Microsoft
- Security Fundamentals Certified 2017 Microsoft
- Cybersecurity: Managing Risk in the Information Age Harvard University
  11394878
- AWS Certification Exam Readiness Workshop: AWS Certified Solutions
  Architect Professional Global Knowledge
- Diploma in DevOps Engineering Kubernetes, Docker and Google Cloud Alison Free Online Learning 1696-3957634
- Google Cloud Platform Fundamentals: Core Infrastructure Coursera SAWDZXH5ZUNN
- Essential Cloud Infrastructure: Foundation Coursera

  EKZT7BTDS3HF
- Essential Cloud Infrastructure: Core Services Coursera NBHVU462A5DM
- Elastic Cloud Infrastructure: Scaling and Automation Coursera
  JNWN43VSV4SP
- Reliable Cloud Infrastructure: Design and Process Coursera
  WFTMDYPS43D3
- Architecting with Google Compute Engine Specialization Coursera

#### CE5Y2QCDF6P2

Serverless Architecture - Lynda.com

OpenShift for Absolute Beginners - Udemy UC-LE7D8ASA

AWS DevOps: Continuous Docker Deployment to AWS Fargate from GitLab - LinkedIn

Aa6k0sMrU\_FHDDLQLJjMYqc90iPs

Docker for Java Developers - LinkedIn

AasDfmtpfhhwn\_dF9pRGxkcm2V39

Google Cloud Platform (GCP) - For Techs - Simplilearn
Certificate code: 2099983

- PRINCE2® Foundation Certification Training Firebrand Training
- Automation with Ansible II: Ansible Tower (DO409) Lynda.com
- Learning the Elastic Stack Lynda.com
- Site Reliability Engineering: Service-Level Agreements and Objectives Lynda.com
  037514
- Learning Path: Developing and Delivering Software with Docker Lynda.com
- AWS Database Migration Simplilearn
  Certificate code : 2275398

#### **Skills**

Continuous Integration • Information Security • Agile & Waterfall Methodologies • Project Management • Web Development • Strategic Planning • Infrastructure • Virtualization • Linux System Administration • Scripting